So, as you know, when we hit into a tree, they just can't disappear, which is really not what we
want.
Instead, we want the trees to slowly grind to a halt.
Now, if you look at the script we have here, basically when we touch the tree sprite, we just stop
all and this stops all code and it's causing a lot of problems.
And this is not just with our trees.
Disappearing is when we stop all our entire game stops.
So this means that we can't add in any restart button, as this button wouldn't work if the code is
all stopped.
So how do we fix this?
Now, this is where I'm going to introduce you to a new block we haven't yet used, which is this broadcast
message code here.
So as you can see, it's very similar to when flag clicked button.
But the key difference is that the script doesn't wait for a when flag click, but instead waits for
a specific message to be broadcast.
For instance, consider a game where a player's sprite encounters a treasure chest.
This event can broadcast a message found treasure, which in turn triggers a script that listens for
found treasure and plays an animation of the chest opening sound effect echoing and the creak of the
lid and the score updating to include the new found treasures.
And it all happens simultaneously.
But that's not all.
The broadcast feature is not just about triggering multiple actions at once.
It's about enhancing control and coordination of your project.
It allows you to create complex, interactive and responsive projects without the clutter of overly
complicated code and and using tons of variables that constantly check if a condition is true or not.
It's sort of like having a conductor leading an orchestra, ensuring each instrument, or in our case,
each sprite, plays at the right time to create a beautiful and harmonious experience.
Right?
With all that said, let's see how we can improve our code with this broadcast feature.
So looking at our code here, instead of stopping all, what I'll do is swap it for this broadcast message
and then click New message and call it player crashed.
Now just broadcasting the message player crashed.
Won't do anything.
We need to now create code that listens for this broadcast.
And to do this we can move into our tree sprite.
And here we can grab this.
When I receive message.
And the message we are looking for is player crashed.
So when we receive this message, we want our trees to come to a halt.
Now the first problem we have is how our trees have a hard coded movement speed at the moment of minus
nine, which doesn't give us much control.
So let's fix this.
And quite simply, we can swap out this minus nine for this movement speed variable that we have already
in our project.
Then moving over to our variable sprite, we can drag in this block and set our movement speed variable
to minus nine at the start of the game.
So now that that is done, we can move back over to our tree sprite.
And now when we receive the message player crashed, we can change our movement speed by 0.5.
And we can use this repeat until block to ensure our trees are at a complete stop.
So we can say repeat until grab this equals block and say movement speed equals zero just like that.
Now, if we give it a test and hit into a tree, you will see that our trees now come to a stop, although
it's still a bit too fast, so we can just add in weight and change it to 0.1 and give it another try.
And there you have it.
Now there's just one problem, and that is how our trees keep spawning in.
And to solve this, all we need to do is grab this, stop all block and change it to stop other scripts
in the sprite.
Then you can just place that right at the end of our script and giving that one more try heading into
a tree.
Well, as you can see, our tree is slowly come to a stop, which makes it look like our player is slowing
down.
Perfecto.